John James Audubon Collection, 1788-1970: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
John James Audubon Collection
1788-1970
C0006
Princeton University Library. Special Collections. Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
5 linear feet 6 boxes 6 bound volume
Audubon, John James, 1785-1851.; Princeton University. Library. Special Collections
John James Audubon (1785-1851) was a nineteenth-century ornithologist, artist, and naturalist who published his illustrations of American birds and quadrupeds. This collection includes several original manuscripts, transcripts and photostats of manuscripts, correspondence of John James and Lucy Bakewell Audubon (originals and copies), and other printed materials related to Audubon, which have been assembled from various sources.
John James Audubon (1785-1851) was an ornithologist, artist, and naturalist, best known for his drawings and paintings of North American birds. Audubon was born Jean Rabin Fougère in Les Cayes, Santo Domingo (now Haiti), the son of Captain Jean Audubon, a French sea captain, plantation owner, and enslaver, and Jeanne Rabin (or Rabine), a French chambermaid. Later in his childhood he moved to France, and when he was 18, he moved to the United States to manage Mill Grove, his family's farm outside of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He married Lucy Bakewell, the daughter of a neighboring landowner in 1808. Audubon began to develop an interest in North American birds as he unsuccessfully moved through careers as a mine owner, a shopkeeper, and a businessman. Eventually settling into whatever odd jobs he could obtain, Audubon began seeking a printer in Europe to publish his drawings of American birds. In 1838, Audubon finally published his The Birds of America through publisher Robert Havell of London. From 1839 until his death in 1851, Audubon remained primarily in New York, working on another edition of his book and a new book, Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America, with his sons.
Consists of materials created by and related to John James Audubon (1785-1851) that were collected from various sources. These include original manuscripts and correspondence, photostat copies and transcripts of additional manuscripts and correspondence, printed materials relating to Audubon's life and work, and files pertaining to a 1959 Princeton University Library exhibition titled "The World of John James Audubon." Much of this material was assembled by Dr. Howard C. Rice, Jr., former head of Special Collections at Princeton University Library.
Original Audubon manuscripts include several descriptions used in his Ornithological Biography (Edinburgh: A. Black, 1831-1839); manuscript descriptions to accompany plates 1-7, 10, 13-17, 19, 23, 25, 28, 31-32, 34, 36, 38, 40-41, and 45 in his Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America (New York: J. J. Audubon, 1845-1848); and over 50 letters by Audubon to Lucy Bakewell Audubon (his wife), John Woodhouse and Victor Gifford Audubon (his sons), Robert Havell (the English engraver of Birds of America), and others. In addition, there are original letters by Lucy Bakewell Audubon, John Woodhouse and Victor Gifford Audubon, John and Julia Bachman, members of the Bakewell family, and Francis Herrick. Accompanying an 1834 letter to Robert Havell is also an original proof for "Summer Red Bird" (plate 44) in Birds of America.
More than 30 photostat copies and 6 bound volumes of Howard Corning's transcripts extend the collection's coverage of Audubon's correspondence. Corning's transcripts also cover Audubon's journals from 1820-1821 and 1840-1843. Subject files of printed materials include clippings, pamphlets, catalogs, and related correspondence pertaining to exhibitions about Audubon, his life in Florida, Robert Havell, portraits by and of Audubon, and Mill Grove, Audubon's Pennsylvania estate. Material related to Princeton's 1959 comprehensive Audubon exhibition includes related correspondence, publicity, and research files.
Collection is open for research use.
This collection was formed as a result of a departmental practice of combining into one collection material of various accessions relating to a particular person, family, or subject. Materials were acquired from various gifts and purchases.
No appraisal information is available.
Publications: Audubon's Ornithological Biography (Edinburgh: A. Black, 1831-1839) and Viviparous Quadrapeds of North America (New York: J. J. Audubon, 1845-1848); Letters of John James Audbon, edited by Howard Corning (1930).
The following sources were consulted during preparation of biographical note: Encyclopedia Britannica Online.
Audubon, John James, 1785-1851 -- Correspondence.; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851 -- Exhibitions.; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851 -- Manuscripts.; Audubon, Lucy Green Bakewell, 1788-1874.; Rice, Howard C. (Howard Crosby), 1904-1980.; Mammals -- United States -- 19th century.; Ornithology -- United States -- 19th century.; Correspondence -- 19th century.; Manuscripts -- 19th century.; Artists -- United States -- 19th century.; Ornithologists -- United States -- 19th century.; Art history; History of science
- Ornithological Biography Vol. III and IV, circa 1827-1839; 7 folders
  Consists of original manuscript descriptions of "Great Cormorant," "Glossy Ibis," and "Purple Gallinule," as well as photostat copies and transcripts of other descriptions used in "Ornithological Biography," Vol. III and IV. There are also some notes and descriptions from Princeton University Library's 1959 exhibition on Audubon.
  - Autograph Manuscript, "Great Cormorant," note, cf. Ornithological Biography. III, 458-469, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Includes original, along with photostat copy and transcript.
    Original acquired by Princeton University Library in 1965.
  - Photostat Copy of Autograph Manuscript, "Glossy Ibis" revised version, Ornithological Biography. IV, 608-611, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    Includes photostat copy and transcript. Original in possession of Mrs. Wharton Sinkler, 631 East Garvers Lane, Philadelphia.
  - Photostat Copy of Autograph Manuscript, "The Wreckers of Florida," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 158-163, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Original in possession of National Audubon Society, New York.
  - Photostat Copy of Autograph Manuscript, "Visits to & from Thomas Bewick," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 300-304, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Photostat Copy of Autograph Manuscript, "A Tough Walk for a Youth," episode, Ornithological Biography., III, 371-375, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Autograph Manuscript, "Purple Gallinule," Ornithological Biography., IV, 37-42, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    Deposit of J.S. Williams (No. 9251).
  - Autograph Manuscript, "Glossy Ibis," Ornithological Biography., IV, 608-611, circa 1827-1839; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- The Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America Vol. I, 1846; AM 15044; 6 folders
  These descriptive notes by John James Audubon, in his hand, were used by John Bachman in preparing the text for the Quadrupeds, first printed in three volumes (1846, 1851, 1854), to accompany the large folio plates (issued in three volumes 1845-1848; 150 plates in all). Comparison of these manuscripts with the printed text shows that Bachman edited the material supplied by Audubon, incorporating most of it in the final version, but with additions, omissions and other modifications. There are marginal notes by Victor G. Audubon and Bachman. There are also some notes and descriptions from Princeton University Library's 1959 exhibition on Audubon.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 1-6, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    Includes:
    (1) "Common American Wild Cat": Plate 1 (text), I, 2-15.
    (2) "Wood-Chuck": Plate 2 (text), I, 16-24.
    (3) "Townsend's Rocky Mountain Hare": Plate 3, I, 25-30.
    (4) "Florida Rat": Plate 4, I, 32-37.
    (5) "Richardson's Columbian Squirrel": Plate 5, I, 41-43.
    (6) "American Cross Fox": Plate 6, I, 45-54.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 7, 10, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    (1) "Carolina Grey Squirrel": Plate 7, I, 55-63.
    (2) "Common American Shrew Mole": Plate 10, I, 81-92.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 13-15, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    (1) "Musk-Rat": Plate 13, I, 108-124.
    (2) "Hudson's Bay Squirrel": Plate 14, I, 125-131.
    (3) "Oregon Flying Squirrel": Plate 15, I, 132-135.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 16, 17, 19, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    (1) "Canada Lynx": Plate 16, I, 136-144.
    (2) "Cat Squirrel": Plate 17, I, 145-150.
    (3) "Soft-Haired Squirrel": Plate 19 (text), I, 157-158.
  - Quadrupeds, nos. 23, 28, 31, 32, 34, 36, 38, 40, 41, 45, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    (1) "Mink" (fragment only): Plate 23 (text), I, 250-260.
    (2) "Common Flying Squirrel": Plate 28 (text), I, 216-222.
    (3) "Collared Peccany": Plate 31, I, 233-241.
    (4) "Polar Hare": Plate 32, I, 242-249.
    (5) "Black Squirrel": Plate 34, I, 261-264.
    (6) "Canada Porcupine": Plate 36, I, 277-286.
    (7) "Red-bellied Squirrel": Plate 38, I, 292-293.
    (8) [American] "White-footed Mouse": Plate 40, I, 300-306.
    (9) "Pennant's Marten": Plate 41, I, 307-315.
    (10) "Wilson's Meadow Mouse": Plate 45, I, 341-346.
  - Quadrupeds, no. 25, 1846; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    "Donny Squirrel": Plate 25 (text), I, 199-201.
- Correspondence, 1788-1963; 3 boxes
  Consists of correspondence of John James Audubon, Lucy Bakewell Audubon, and others, including original letters as well as photostat copies and typed transcripts.
  This series is arranged into five groupings: Letters Relating to Lucy Bakewell Audubon; John James Audubon Letters (Originals), Letters of Others (Originals), John James Audubon Letters (Photostat Copies), and Letters of Others (Photostat Copies).
  - Letters Relating to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, 1788-1963; 12 folders
    Consists of correspondence from Lucy Bakewell Audubon, who was married to John James Audubon, and family members, primarily to Miss Gifford. There is also some later material created by Dr. Howard C. Rice, Jr., in relation to his article about Lucy Bakewell Audubon in the Princeton University Library Chronicle.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Chronicle Article and Notes by H. C. Rice, Jr., Regarding "Mr. Audubon's Lucy", 1963; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      Includes inventories of Princeton's Lucy Bakewell Audubon letters.
    - Lucy Bakewell Audubon Letters to Miss (& Mrs.) Gifford, 1803-1838; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      7 letters. Originals. Postscript: New Orleans, 11 April 1821, by J. J. Audubon on Lucy's letter of 1 April, 1821.
      Purchased at Sotheby sale, 2 July 1962.
    - Photostat Copies of Lucy Bakewell Audubon Letters to Miss (& Mrs.) Gifford, 1803-1838; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      7 letters. Photostats and transcripts of B1 F10.
    - Description of Audubon-Bakewell Correspondence with Miss Gifford in Stark Collection, 1963; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      Description of Audubon Material in the Collection of H. J. Lutcher Stark, Orange, Texas.
    - Photostat Copy of John James Audubon Letter to William Bakewell, La Gerbetière, 1805 May 20; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      Photostat of B2 F1 - also see note for B1 F14.
    - Photostat Copy of William Bakewell Letter to Miss Gifford Fatland Ford, Pennsylvania, 1805 July 19; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      Enclosing the above letter from John James Audubon 1805 May 20. Original letter of William Bakewell not acquired by Princeton. Original Audubon letter in B2 F1.
    - Ann Bakewell Gordon Letters to Mrs. Gifford, 1831 April 4-August 14; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      2 Letters. Originals. Dated 1831 April 4 and 1831 August 14 (mentioning her sister Mrs. Audubon); also: Miss M. A. Coltman to Mrs. Gifford 1838 (mention of letter from Mrs. Audubon).
      Purchased at Sotheby Sale, 2 July 1962.
    - Benjamin Bakewell, et al., Letters to Miss Gifford, et al., 1788-1829; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      28 letters. Originals.
      18 letters were purchased at Sotheby Sale, 2 July 1962, and 10 additional letters not in sales catalogue were purchased subsequently in 1963 from Sotheby's.
    - William Bakewell Letters to Miss Gifford, 1801-1808; AM 17707; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      3 letters. Originals, with transcripts.
      Purchased from Sotheby's, 1962-1963.
    - Photostat Copies of Benjamin Bakewell, et al., Letters to Miss Gifford, et al., 1788-1829; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      Photostats and transcripts of B1 F16.
    - Transcripts of John James and Lucy Audubon Letters to Benjamin Phillips and Family, 1837; AM 2009-3; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      Typewritten transcripts only. Originals in possession of Phillips descendants in England.
    - Photostat Copies of Ann Bakewell Gordon Letters to Mrs. Gifford, 1831-1838; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      Photostats of B1 F15.
  - John James Audubon Letters (Originals), 1805 May 20-1855; 56 folders
    Consists primarily of letters from John James Audubon to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, with additional letters to Robert Havell, Victor Audubon, and Thomas McCulloch. Many originals are accompanied by photostat copies, transcripts, and materials related to acquisitions and provenance.
    - Letter to William Bakewell, La Gerbetiere, 1805 May 20; AM 17555; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Letter to Charles d'Orbigny, New York, 1807 April 29; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Deposition of Laverty Repayment to Audubon & Bakewell for Shipment of Tobacco, New Orleans, 1817-1820 August 10; AM 18769; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Liverpool, 1826 September 3; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Edinburgh, 1826 December 9; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 May 15; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, London, 1827 June 20; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 November 25-28; 1827 November 27-28; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Liverpool, 1827 December 21; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, London, 1828 November 2; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Letter Fragment to Victor G. Audubon, London, 1829; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Letter to Robert Havell with Instructions for Re-engraving Legends, Edinburgh, 1831 March 2; AM 15808; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Original. Oversize.
      Gift of Elizabeth C. Chambers in 1957.
    - Letter to Robert Havell, Edinburgh, 1831 March 26; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Letter to Edward Everett, St. Augustine, East Florida, 1832 February 1; AM 19639; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Boston, 1833 May 4; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      Deposit of J. S. Williams (No. 9251).
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Boston, 1833 May 4; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon with Postscript by John Woodhouse Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 14; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 18; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 19; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 22; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Letter to Richard Harlan, M.D., Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 26; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 May 27; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 June 4; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon. P.S. by John Woodhouse Audubon, Eastport, Maine, 1833 June 5-6; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Bras d'Or, Labrador, 1833 August 5; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Charleston, S.C., 1833 November 9; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Letter to Robert Havell, Charleston, S.C., with Original Proof for Plate 44, Birds of America, "Summer Red Bird", 1834 January 16; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Letter to John Bachman, Baltimore, 1834 March 13; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Letter to Robert Havell, New York, 1834 April 8; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Manchester, 1834 September 5; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Liverpool, 1834 September 13-16; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1834 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Letter to Walter Horton Bentley, London, 1835 March 17; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Letter to Benjamin & John Gott, London, 1836 February 5; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Letter to R. O. Anderson, London, 1836 May 16; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Letter to Robert Havell, Charleston, 1836 December 18; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Letter to Ward & Bell, Charleston, 1837 June 13; AM 18768; 1 folder (Folder 34)
      Signature is cut off.
    - Letter to Thomas Nuttall, London, 1837 September 19; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Edinburgh, 1838 July 1; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Letter by Victor G. Audubon to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Edinburgh, 1838 July 10; 1 folder (Folder 37)
      With postscript by John J. Audubon.
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon, Edinburgh, 1838 August 1; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Letter to Mrs. A. C. Alison, Edinburgh, 1838 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Letter to John Calvert, Edinburgh, 1839 February 26; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Letter to John W. Audubon, with Postscript by Lucy Audubon, Edinburgh, 1839 May 23; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Audubon, Lucy. Letter to Victor G. & John W. Audubon, Edinburgh, 1839 June 30-July 2; 1 folder (Folder 42)
      With Postscript by John J. Audubon.
    - Letter to John Woodhouse Audubon, Washington, D.C., 1840 April 3-5; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Letter to George Parkman, Lowell, Mass, 1840 August 26; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Boston, 1840 September 14; 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - Letter to John Woodhouse Audubon, Boston, 1840 September 20; 1 folder (Folder 45)
    - Letter to F. L. Alden, New York, 1841 January 27; AM 16910; 1 folder (Folder 46)
    - Letter to Thomas McCulloch, Jr., New York, 1841 June 26; 1 folder (Folder 47)
    - Letter to Increase S. Smith, New York, 1841 August 15; 1 folder (Folder 48)
    - Letter to Col. J. J. Abert, New York, 1842 July 4; AM 17303; 1 folder (Folder 49)
    - Letter to Lucy Bakewell Audubon and Sons, Quebec, 1842 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 50)
    - Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 2; 1 folder (Folder 51)
    - Letter to J. W. Audubon, with Postscript by Victor G. Audubon, Minnie's Land, 1847 January 28; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 52)
    - Carte de Visite Photographs of John James Audubon and Lucy Bakewell Audubon, circa 1848-1855; AM 16663; 1 folder (Folder 53)
  - Letters of Others (Originals), 1825 January 4-1918; 7 folders
    Consists of letters from Lucy Audubon, Victor Audubon, and John and Julia Bachman.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Lucy Bakewell Audubon Letter to Prof. Joseph Henry, Washington Heights, N.Y., 1863 August 14; AM 17324; 1 folder (Folder 54)
    - Lucy Bakewell Audubon Letter to Mary Gaskell, 1836 May 10; AM 2008-56; 1 folder (Folder 54A)
      2 pages, with printed card of Victor G. Audubon (son).
      Purchased at auction in 2008.
    - Victor G. Audubon Letter to J. T. Bowen, New York, 1847 April 14; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 55)
    - Victor G. Audubon Letter to John Bohlem, New York, 1854 May 11; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 56)
    - John Bachman Letter to Joseph Bevan, Charleston, S.C., 1825 January 4; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 57)
    - Julia R. Bachman Letter to Ruthven Deane, Columbia, S.C., 1903 January 10; AM 18233; 1 folder (Folder 58)
    - Francis H. Herrick Letters to Edwin H. Johnson, Cleveland, 1918; AM 18786; 1 folder (Folder 59)
      3 letters.
  - Letters of John James Audubon (Photostat Copies), 1807 April 29-1843 June 13; 27 folders
    Consists of photostat copies and transcripts of letters from John James Audubon, primarily to Victor Audubon.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Charles d'Orbigny, New York, 1807 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 60)
      Photocopy of B2 F2. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Prather & Jacob Promissory Note, Louisville, KY, 1819 September 15; 1 folder (Folder 61)
      Original in the collection of Seymour Adelman, Philadelphia.
    - Photstat Copies of Letters and Memo to Baron de la Bouillerie, Paris, 1828 September 13-1828 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 62)
      Copies of 2 letters. Originals in the Archives Nationales, Paris.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Robert Havell with Instructions for Re-engraving Legends, Edinburgh, 1831 March 2; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Oversize. Photocopy of B6 F6.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Robert Havell, Edinburgh, 1831 March 26; 1 folder (Folder 63)
      Photocopy of B2 F12. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Charleston, S.C., 1833 November 9; 1 folder (Folder 64)
      Photocopy of B2 F25. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Robert Havell, New York, 1834 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 65)
      Photocopy of B2 F28. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to W. H. Bentley, London, 1835 March 17; 1 folder (Folder 66)
      Photocopy of B2 F30. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to R. O. Anderson, London, 1836 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 67)
      Photocopy of B2 F32.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Robert Havell, Charleston, S.C., 1836 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 68)
      Photocopy of B2 F33. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Receipt to Dr. S. G. Morton & Joseph P. Smith for Philadelphia Academy of Natural Sciences Subscription to Birds of America, 1837 July 1; AM 17484; 1 folder (Folder 69)
      Original in the possession of Mr. Robert L. Walsh, Jr., 3424 Prospect St. NW, Washington, D.C.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to John Calvert, Edinburgh, 1839 February 26; 1 folder (Folder 70)
      Photocopy of B2 F40. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to George Parkman, Lowell, Massachusetts, 1840 August 26; 1 folder (Folder 71)
      Photocopy of B2 F43. Original acquired by PUL in 1965.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Louisville, 1843 March 19-20; 1 folder (Folder 72)
      Original in National Audubon Society, New York.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Mrs. Audubon, Ohio River, 1843 March 23; 1 folder (Folder 73)
      Incomplete. Original in National Audubon Society, NY.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 March 28; 1 folder (Folder 74)
      Original in National Audubon Society, NY.
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 March 31; 1 folder (Folder 75)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 76)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 17; 1 folder (Folder 77)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Louis, 1843 April 23; 1 folder (Folder 78)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, St. Charles, 1843 April 25; 1 folder (Folder 79)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Boonville, Missouri, 1843 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 80)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Black Snake Hills, Missouri, 1843 May 5; 1 folder (Folder 81)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Council Bluffs, Missouri Territory, 1843 May 8; 1 folder (Folder 82)
    - Photostat Copy of Letter to Victor G. Audubon, Fort Fierre, 1843 June 1; 1 folder (Folder 83)